♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
["Mr. Tailor" playing]
- ♪ Fix it ♪
- ♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
♪ Holding the scissors ♪
♪ One cut, and it's over ♪
[Karla] What are you doing
here at the shop?
[Uno] I came to have a suit made.
They told me this is really
the best place. Good tailoring.
[Gavin on the phone, in English]
Did you kill Grandpa?
We'll talk about it when you get home.
Our deal was that today,
you'll give us back the kid.
The child already believes I'm her mother.
Can we just make it real?
[in English] Of course not.
Audrey escaped,
and the child is the only way
to bring Audrey back here,
so she won't speak.
[Martina] Just think what Atoy will do
when he finds out Ibyang
is really his child.
PREVIOUSLY
Ibyang is Atoy's child?
[in English] That's none of your business.
I'll tell Atoy everything.
- Ouch, ouch!
- [in English] Not so fast!
[grunts and groans]
- [Karla] We don't even know him.
- [keypad beeping]
He just suddenly appeared here.
[Charmi] You know Ibyang's real parent?!
- It's Atoy.
- [in English] For real?!
[Paldo] Isn't his mission finished yet?
This is the longest time
he hasn't sent word while on a mission.
I don't know the access code.
[Uno] Do you know the combinations?
[in English] Do you know this woman?
[in English] Don't tell me
that you don't know them.
Don't drag them into this.
[in English] But I will
make her scream in pain.
[grunts]
[gasps]
[music fades]
Oh, miss, I'll go to the shop first.
I'll lend Paldo some clothes.
I'll check there.
Maybe some things survived the fire.
You can borrow Atoy's T-Shirt
from his room.
Ah, can I?
Maybe even borrow his briefs.
- Oh.
- Atoy's.
You're ridiculous.
Looks like it, huh. [chuckles]
Mom! Brother Emerson! Is Uno inside?
He is. Why?
You shouldn't have let him in.
- Why?
- Huh?
I think he's a spy.
Maybe he works for Red Regalia.
- What?! Are you sure?
- Huh?
[suspicious music playing]
- [device blips]
- Caught you!
[Karla] I knew it. My suspicion was right!
[growls]
[grunts and groans]
[Karla shouts]
[Uno] I know Atoy!
- [Karla] You think you can escape!
- [Uno] Mercado sent me!
[suave theme music playing]
[music fades]
Sorry, everyone.
I didn't introduce myself right away.
[Cita inhales]
The truth is that
I didn't want anyone else to know.
Because national security is at stake.
Actually, I work for Colonel Mercado.
[pensive music playing]
[Emerson] Ahh.
Is that so?
Oh, so that's why your moves
are similar to Atoy's moves and mine.
Right? So cool. Like Chuck Norris action.
[chuckles]
So, you're a tracker too,
like Brother Atoy?
That's right, and Sir Padua
is our primary, and he's the best.
[Emerson] Hmm.
You know, actually,
I really want to be a tracker too.
- [Uno] Really?
- Yes. I think I can.
Because I've been with Atoy,
so I know what to do.
Where do you apply for an interview?
Where do you submit a biodata?
I want to apply.
Because I have medical clearance.
It's complete.
- I have SSS too.
- Emerson!
- Emerson, stop.
- And I also have…
I also have, ah…
Later. Ask questions later
about changing your career.
- But if I have complete…
- Enough for now.
The important question now is,
why are you here?
I need to secure the laptop
that was turned over to Sir Padua.
[in English] Laptop, laptop.
- Wait.
- [suspicious music playing]
[Atoy] This is the device I extracted
from the Zahran Embassy, sir.
Why is it here again?
[Mercado on the tablet] I'll send you
the details of your mission.
[in English] But this laptop
is for your safekeeping.
That's the one… That's…
That's the one your boss sent here?
- The one in the…
- [Uno] Oh, oh…
hard case, like for a gun?
- [Uno, in English] Yes, exactly.
- The heavy one? That one?
[Emerson] I was here then!
I was with Atoy when it was sent here.
- I saw it.
- So, where is it hidden?
I didn't see.
I don't know where Atoy put it.
Of course, he was the one who hid it.
- [sneaky music playing]
- [Cita stammers]
You're so confusing to talk to.
Wait, wait.
If you really work with Atoy,
why don't you just ask him?
Where is he?
[in English] He's compromised.
What?!
[pensive music playing]
We tried calling him,
and we went to his last location.
But he's really missing in action.
And we suspect he was captured.
What do you mean?!
Something happened to him?!
What? Is Atoy okay?!
- Is he alive?!
- Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom.
- Miss, miss.
- Don't say that.
- [Emerson] Miss. Sit down first, miss.
- [gasps]
- No.
- Sit down first, miss.
- He's okay…
- [pensive music playing]
I'm very sorry, but we really don't know.
But I'm being honest with you.
- [Cita whimpers]
- Everything you fear could happen.
My God. [sobs]
[Cita] So-- How--
Who can we ask?
Where can we go to find him?
What… What can we do?
[tense music playing]
[Cita] Oh my God.
[Red] Zip it up.
[mysterious music playing]
[ominous music playing]
[ambulance siren wailing]
I hope you catch those thieves.
I never thought it would come to this.
I lost my father because of them.
Don't worry, sir.
We'll do everything we can.
And if you can follow us to the station,
to give your official statement.
[in English] I'll be there with my lawyer.
All right, sir. Our condolences.
[sighs]
[line ringing]
[phone ringing]
[suspicious music playing]
[in English] Yes?
[Red on the phone] Where are you?
Do you have Ibyang with you?
[in English] No, not yet.
Olga ran away from me.
[in English] But don't worry.
Our men are searching for her as we speak.
This night has way too many screw-ups.
[in English] We need that kid.
Come back here.
[tense music playing]
[music fades]
Lord.
[sobs]
I know You see everything.
I believe You have not abandoned Atoy.
[melodramatic music playing]
Who's that?
The one on your necklace.
Saint Anthony of Padua.
Patron of lost people.
[Lily] Have you prayed to him?
If that saint helps find the lost,
maybe it can be reversed?
Maybe he can help
stop Samir from finding
your child and her mother.
[Atoy] Please, Saint Anthony.
Please provide safety
for Audrey and Janine.
And also, the people
who are important to me.
[Cita] And if he's in danger…
[sobs]
Save him, Lord.
[Atoy] Give me strength too
to overcome this trial.
[sobs]
I pray he comes home.
[sobbing]
[Atoy] So I can still be
with my family, Saint Anthony,
and the people important to me.
[winces] Ouch.
So dramatic.
In a fight, you're not afraid to get hurt.
Just a little alcohol and you act like…
It stings!
Of course, it's the face.
It stings, right?
So, your toughness is fake?
And your cuteness is fake too.
[Uno] Mmm-hmm.
Because the truth is,
you just want to get inside
Brother Atoy's house.
[light music playing]
Sorry, but you can't fool me.
[clicks tongue, sighs]
Sorry.
That's really my mission.
To get inside
and take the laptop, that's all.
I understand.
That's also Brother Atoy's job.
To pretend for the mission.
Honestly, I really admire Brother Atoy.
So, you admire me too?
Ouch, ouch! What's wrong? You…
Are you angry?
Or you just can't admit the truth?
[pensive music playing]
You know, Karla,
when I first saw you,
I really found you beautiful.
Yes. That's not fake.
How about you?
Can you admit to me that you like me too?
I won't admit anything to you
because I don't like you.
Really?
Why? Are you taken?
Or maybe… Maybe you already
like someone else?
[Uno] Hmm?
[in English] Yes.
[in English] Silence means yes, Karla.
[music fades]
But you're not sure.
Because I think
I'm better than the one you like.
Since you didn't answer me right away.
[pensive music playing]
Whatever.
Think whatever you want.
[in English] Okay.
If Atoy is missing…
…I'm sure he'll be found.
Let's trust Saint Anthony of Padua.
- Yes, Father.
- [Nestor] Yes.
[Nestor] Father is right.
Atoy even shares
the same name as our saint.
I'm sure he won't be abandoned.
To be sure, we'll hold a vigil for him.
Right, Father?
Yes, and…
I'll also help find a sponsor,
so that even if the vigil lasts all night,
the people of Tabang Lupa won't go hungry.
There. Count me in.
[in English] Free pares mami
for the first vigil.
I'll help you, Uncle.
Thank you so much, everyone.
But I think Brother Atoy
just went on vacation.
Of course, maybe he was sad
after losing Ibyang.
Where could he have gone?
Why, miss? Are you going with him?
Oh my.
- I was just asking.
- [horn honks in the distance]
Who's arriving?
Who's that?
[tires screech]
- It's Audrey.
- [door clicks shut]
[Ame and Cita] Audrey!
Audrey, it's late.
What are you doing here?
Why do you look like that?
You don't have pants.
[stammers] Oh, uh-- So-- Sorry.
Um, um…
[in English] It's a long story, but…
We're okay for now. Um…
Is Atoy here?
- [tense music playing]
- [muttering]
We're looking for him. We need his help.
Oh, no, Atoy isn't here.
We don't know where he is.
Atoy is missing.
[music swells]
You've been through a lot, Audrey.
You two should pray, okay.
[somber music playing]
You should rest now too.
Poor Janine.
So young, yet she's gone through so much.
[pensive music playing]
Thank you again.
Sorry for the trouble.
No, no. Don't worry about that.
Go upstairs now.
Stay in your old room, Janine.
[Audrey] Janine.
Come on.
Get some rest.
Thank you.
[phone ringing]
[in English] Mom?
[in English] Gavin, please.
[in English] Come home. For me?
Everything your father does
is to keep the family together.
No. I won't come home.
And don't look for me.
[in English] Gavin, please.
[in English] I don't want to lose you.
[in English] Please, come home. Please?
[in English] No!
[in English] He's evil!
[suspicious music playing]
[Gavin, in English] Don't make me accept
that evil is normal!
Mom, I don't care if you both cut me off.
[in English] Okay?
[in English] I don't want to be a Regalia.
And I'm ashamed to be the child
of your husband!
[Gavin on the phone] Mom, I love you.
But you're also enabling
Dad's evil behavior.
[in English] I can't be part
of something like that. I'm sorry.
[in English] I'm sorry, Mom, but…
Let's forget each other.
[Gavin sobs]
[sharp inhale]
[music fades]
[in English] S-Sorry.
Gavin, come in.
Sit down.
Sorry again.
[pensive music playing]
You don't need to apologize.
Honestly, I should apologize to you.
Because I thought
you were like your father.
But now I realize you're different.
You're good.
Because you even took Audrey
and Janine away from them.
Thank you.
It's okay.
I still carry our surname, so…
It's unavoidable that people think
I'm like him too.
No.
The sins of the father
are not the sins of the child.
Do you understand that?
Miss Cita.
Is Karla here?
I just want to talk to her.
I'm sorry again about your wound.
No. It's fine.
It was my fault
for not introducing myself
to you right away.
[in English] Thank you.
[Uno sighs]
[Uno] I'll go home now.
Maybe tomorrow I'll figure out
how we can enter the secret room.
For sure, the laptop
I'm looking for is there.
Okay. I'll try to help you tomorrow.
- That's a promise, huh.
- Yes!
I'm sure.
[clicks tongue] Wait.
[light music playing]
[in English] Why are you touching Karla?
- Who are you?
- [chair scrapes]
[unsettling music playing]
Ah, he's Brother Atoy's colleague.
This is Gavin, my friend.
Uno, by the way.
- [in English] Future boyfriend of Karla.
- What?
Really?
[in English] Manifesting.
[music fades]
You've slept here before, child,
so I'm sure you'll be comfortable.
The two of us fit perfectly here.
Janine.
[Janine sniffles]
Please talk to me.
Where's Daddy, Mommy?
I thought he was here?
And didn't you say
we were going to the US?
[pensive music playing]
Uncle Red and Aunt Martina,
why did they do that?
Why are they like that?
Why did they lock us up?
Mommy, I don't want to say this, but…
will they kill us?
What if…
What if they follow us here?
Daddy should be here
to protect us.
Janine, listen to me.
We're safe here.
But how can we be safe
if Daddy isn't here?
[tense music playing]
[melancholic music playing]
[dramatic sting]
[music fades]
[somber music playing]
Where are you, Atoy?
So much has happened here,
and still no word from you.
Your child and her mother are here.
They're waiting for you.
They need you.
Where are you?
[pensive music playing]
And…
You know I don't like it.
I'm the most handsome here.
So, what if…
What if I got burned in that fire?
Who would be the handsome one
left in our community?
That can't happen.
So please, Atoy.
Come back, please.
[mysterious voice] Psst.
‪[quirky sting]
[mysterious music playing]
Who's that?
Audrey?
Ame?
Janine?
[titters]
Don't scare me, okay?
You, huh.
You think I don't know it's you?
[sneaky music playing]
[quirky sting]
Tonet?
Netchai, is that you?
- [mysterious voice] Psst!
- [whimpers]
[playful music playing]
[mysterious voice] Psst!
[shrieks]
[music fades]
[playful music playing]
[mysterious voice] Psst.
- [mysterious voice] Psst.
- [gasps]
Son of a thread.
[intense music playing]
Olga's child is dead.
I'm not fake. Why are you saying I'm fake?
Olga is a scammer.
So, for sure, you're her fake child!
UP NEXT
[Emerson] A special personal mission
must be done
by the children of the thread.
We'll call this "Operation Atoy…
Where are you?"
The ambassador's bodyguard.
His name is Samir.
I have a strong feeling
he's the reason why Atoy is missing.
[grunting and groaning]
[groaning]
♪ One cut, and it's over ♪
♪ Fix it ♪
Subtitle translation by: Rachel C. Arias